MANOJ KUMAR P

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

Visit Portfolio

No 96, 11th Main Road, Sector 6, HSR Layout, Bangalore, Karnataka India - 560102 manojkumarp@outlook.com +919940045810

ABOUT ME

I am a confident and self-motivated Machine Learning Engineer with two years of experience, including internships. My expertise encompasses a wide range of tools and technologies, including Python, OpenCV, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Docker, and AWS, I a keen on developing and deploying innovative machine learning solutions. I am committed to continuous learning and contributing to positive, productive work environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AI/ML Engineer - 2 09/2024 - Present

Hacklab Solutions Private Limited, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Have been actively working on improving the tracking algorithm by integrating various techniques such as stag markers, feature extration for object re-identification.

12/2023 - 08/2024 AI/ML Engineer - 1

Hacklab Solutions Private Limited, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Have developed the complete training pipeline along with modules for the product line ranging from image processing to object detection, tracking and facial recognition.

AI/ML Trainee Engineer 03/2023 - 11/2023

Hacklab Solutions Private Limited, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Developed scripts to automate the training process for developing various models used, along with implementing license plate recognition module.

08/2022 - 02/2023 AI/ML Intern

Hacklab Solutions Private Limited, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Set up CVAT for annotation and automated task handling with scripts. Enhanced the safety gear detection models for improved accuracy.

Freelance Developer 09/2020 - 11/2021

Tamil Nadu, India

Collaboratively worked on various projects in the domains of web and mobile application development for clients from India and abroad.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Kongu Engineering College Erode, Tamil Nadu, India | 2019 - 2023

CGPA: 8.62

AISSCE (HSC)

Major in Computer Science, Maths Devi Academy Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India | 2017 - 2019

AISSE (SSC)

Thamarai International School Thanjavur, Tamil Nadu, India | 2016 - 2017

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Big Data Stack: Linux, Python (Numpy, Matplotlab, Pandas, OpenCV)
- Pytorch, Tensorflow
- · Docker, AWS
- Object Detection, Recognition, Tracking and NLP
- Linear Algebra, Statistics

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork, multitasking, detailing, time management
- Presentation skill, active listening
- Analysis, logical thinking, decision making

Marks: 86.6%

Marks: 95.0%